sharepointmaven.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy - SharePoint Maven

**Effective Date: September 1, 2018**

Protecting your private information is our priority at SharePoint Maven, Inc. This Privacy Policy informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data of Users of the Website and/or Services. SharePoint Maven attaches great importance to ensuring that your personal data and crawled data are collected, used, processed and erased in accordance with the current applicable regulations as stipulated by local, state, national, federal, and other data protection legislation. Protecting your data is a matter of great importance to our company. If you have requests concerning your personal information or any questions, please contact us at greg@sharepointmaven.com.

If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue use of the Website and our Services.

## **Definitions**

For purposes of this Privacy Policy references to “ **Customer** ” mean a registered, paying purchaser of the Services.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy references to “ **us** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our** ,” and/or “ **SharePoint Maven** ” mean Share Point Maven, Inc., a Massachusetts corporation with a principal place of business located at P.O. Box 1329, Summit, NJ 07902-1329, USA, and its subsidiaries, parents, and affiliates.

References to the “ **Services** ” mean any and all services offered by us, including but not limited to SharePoint-related services, such as consulting and coaching,

References to the “ **Website** ” mean the Website bearing the URL **[www.sharepointmaven.com](https://sharepointmaven.com/)** as well as any other site owned and/or operated by or under any of our trade names.

References to “ **you** ,” and/or “ **User** ,” mean the User of the Website and/or purchaser of the Services.

## **Agreement to be Bound**

The following Data Protection and Privacy Policy Statement governs the collection and use of private information via the Website and the Services. By accessing the Website and/or registering for the use of our Services you represent that you have read and understood the Privacy Policy and that you agree to be bound by thereby.

This Privacy Policy may be additionally subject to our Terms of Sale for those Customers who purchase our Services.

## **Modifications and Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may modify, add to, suspend, or delete the Privacy Policy, in whole or in part, at our sole discretion at any time, with such modifications, additions or deletions being effective thirty (30) calendar days following their posting to the Web and emailing a notice to registered Users. Your access of the Website and/or use of our Services, after modification, addition or deletion of the Privacy Policy shall be deemed to constitute acceptance by you of the modification, addition or deletion.

## **Collection of your Personal Information**

We collect both personally-identifiable information or personal data and non-personally-identifiable information from you. Often, you choose what information to provide to us, but, sometimes, we may require certain information for you to use and for us to provide the Services. Specifically, we collect the following:

_**Registration & Account Set Up**. _In order to register you as a Customer, provide you with support, and process your transactions, we will collect personal data, which may include your full name; telephone number; email address; and corporate contact information.

In addition, you should note that our payment processors, including PayPal Manager and QuickBooks, may collect and store sensitive financial information, including your credit card number, expiration date, and billing details for those Customers who pay us via credit card and bank account for those Customers who pay via bank transfer. We store the same only as anonymous data and have no access to or control over the sensitive financial information you may provide.

### HubSpot CRM

_**Automated Information:**  _SharePoint Maven automatically receives and records information from each User’s browser or your mobile device when you visit the Website, such as your IP address in an anonymized fashion or unique device identifier, cookies and data about which pages you visit in order to allow us to operate and provide the Website, and data about the type of device you use to connect to our Website. This information is stored in log files and is collected automatically. We may combine this information from your browser or your mobile device with other information that we or our partners collect about you, including across devices. This information is used to prevent fraud and to keep the Website secure, to analyze and understand how the Services work for our Users, and to provide advertising, including across your devices, and a more customized Website experience for members and visitors.

We may also automatically collect device-specific information when you access or use our Website. This information may include information such as the hardware model, operating system information, browser information, IP address, and device identifiers.

**_Location Information:_**  We may collect information about your use of the Website for advertising, analytics, to serve content and to protect the Website, including your IP address, browser information (including referrers), device information (such as iOS IDFA, IDFV for limited non-advertising purposes, Android AAID, and, when enabled by you, location information provided by your device). We may obtain location information you provide in your profile or your IP address. With your consent, we may also determine location by using other information from your devices, such as general location information from GPS or information about wireless networks or cell towers near your mobile device. We may use and store information about your location to provide features and to improve and customize the Website, for example, for our internal analytics and performance monitoring; localization, regional requirements, and policies for the Website; for local content, search results, and recommendations; for mapping the Website; and (using non-precise location information) marketing. If you have consented to share your precise device location details but would no longer like to continue sharing that information with us, you may revoke your consent to the sharing of that information through the settings on your mobile device. Certain non-precise location services, such as for security and localized policies based on your IP address or submitted address, are critical for the site to function. We will only share your geo-location details with third parties (like our mapping, payments, or, to the extent applicable, advertising providers) in order to provide you with the Website and the Services that you have purchased.

**_Analytics Information:_**  We use data analytics to ensure site functionality and improve the Services and our Website. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information that you submit.

## **Use of your Personal Information**

We may use your personally identifiable information to process transactions; to provide and improve customer service administration; to personalize your User experience; to contact Users via e-mail or telephone; to respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions; to send company news, updates and other related info via our mailing list; and to facilitate registration for and use of our Services.

We may use your non-personally identifiable information to create traffic statistics for our Website; to create User statistics for our Services; to improve customer service, and to personalize your User experience.

SharePoint Maven gives you the choice of providing, editing or removing certain information, as well as choices about how we contact you. You may change or correct your SharePoint Maven information or request deletion by contacting us at [**greg@sharepointmaven.com**](mailto:greg@sharepointmaven.com).

Depending on your location, you may also have certain additional rights with respect to your information, such as: (i) data access and portability (including the right to obtain a copy of your personal data you provided to SharePoint Maven, via your settings); (ii) data correction (including the ability to update your personal data, in many cases via settings); (iii) data deletion (including the right to have SharePoint Maven delete your personal information, except information we are required to retain, by contacting us); and (iv) withdrawal of consent or objection to processing (including, in limited circumstances, the right to ask SharePoint Maven to stop processing your personal data, with some exceptions, by contacting us).

You may also control the receipt of certain types of communications from SharePoint Maven. SharePoint Maven may send you messages about the Services or your activity. Some of these messages are required, service-related messages for Users (such as transactional messages or legal notices). Other messages are not required, such as newsletters. You can control which optional messages you choose to receive via the unsubscribe link in our emails.

If you no longer wish to use the Website or purchase Services from us or receive service-related messages (except for legally required notices), then you may close your account.

## **Sharing Information with Third Parties**

SharePoint Maven does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties.

SharePoint Maven may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or provided marketing services, such as MailChimp. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide services to SharePoint Maven, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

SharePoint Maven may disclose your personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on SharePoint Maven or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of SharePoint Maven; and/or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of SharePoint Maven, or the public.

## **Automatically Collected Information**

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by SharePoint Maven. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the Website, to maintain the quality of the Website, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the SharePoint Maven Website.

## **Use of Cookies**

The SharePoint Maven Website may use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize SharePoint Maven pages, or register with SharePoint Maven site or purchase Services, a cookie helps SharePoint Maven to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same SharePoint Maven website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the SharePoint Maven features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the SharePoint Maven Services or websites you visit.

## **Security of your Personal Information**

SharePoint Maven secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.

In addition, access to your data is restricted to need-to-access individuals.

We strive to take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or alteration of your personal information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations inherent to the Internet which are beyond our control; and (b) security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Site cannot be guaranteed. Please note that non-encrypted communication using email is not secure. Thus, we cannot guarantee data security in email communication and, therefore, recommend using physical mail for confidential information.

## **International Transfer**

We operate globally so it is necessary to transfer your information internationally. In particular, your information will likely be transferred to and processed via servers located in the United States. The Canada, the United States, European Economic Area (“EEA”) Member States, and other countries all have different laws. When your information is moved from your home country to another country, the laws and rules that protect your personal information in the country to which your information is transferred may be different from those in the country in which you live. For example, the circumstances in which law enforcement can access personal information may vary from country to country. In particular, if your information is in the United States, it may be accessed by government authorities in accordance with U.S. law.

To the extent that SharePoint Maven is deemed to transfer personal information outside of the EEA, we rely separately, alternatively, and independently on the following legal bases to transfer your information:

**_Model Clauses._** The European Commission has adopted standard contractual clauses (also known as Model Clauses), which provide safeguards for personal information that is transferred outside of Europe. We often use these Model Clauses when transferring personal information outside of Europe. You can request a copy of our Model Clauses by emailing greg@sharepointmaven.com.

_P **rivacy Shield.**_ SharePoint Maven does not participate in Privacy Shield at this time. However, SharePoint Maven may rely on the EU-US Privacy Shield to transfer personal information to some of our third-party service providers in the United States, where they are certified to receive such information under the [Privacy Shield Program](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

_Necessary for the performance of the contract._ SharePoint Maven provides a voluntary service; you can choose whether or not you want to purchase the Services. However, if you want to purchase the Services, you need to agree to our Terms of Sale which set out the contract between SharePoint Maven and its Customers. As we operate in countries worldwide (including in the United States) and may use technical infrastructure in the United States to deliver the Services to you, in accordance with the contract between us, we need to transfer your personal information to the United States and to other jurisdictions as necessary to provide the Services. Simply put, we can’t provide you with the Services and perform our contract with you without moving your personal information around the world.

## **Children Under Thirteen** **; Notice to Minors**

SharePoint Maven does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use the Website and Services. We request that all users of the Website and our Services who are under the age of thirteen not disclose or provide any personally identifiable information. If we discover that a child under thirteen has provided us with personally-identifiable information, we will delete that child’s personally identifiable information from our records. You are responsible for any and all account activity conducted by a minor under your account.

In addition to protecting the privacy of children under age thirteen, we are committed to protect the privacy of minors. Though neither our Website nor our Services are not targeted to minors nor is it intended to be used by minors, if, for any reason, a minor has shared information via our Website and/or Services said minor may request and obtain removal of such information by contacting us at [**greg@sharepointmaven.com**](mailto:greg@sharepointmaven.com). Although we offer deletion capability, you should be aware that the removal of content may not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of that content or information provided.

## **Do Not Track Disclosure**

Please note that while you may have the opportunity to opt-out of targeted advertising as discussed in the “How to Opt-Out” section above, and you may be able to control the use of cookies through your Web browser as described in the “Use of Cookies” section below, some Web browsers may also give you the ability to enable a “do not track” setting. This setting sends a special signal to the Websites you encounter while Web browsing. This “do not track” signal is different from disabling certain forms of tracking by declining cookies in your browser settings, as browsers with the “do not track” setting enabled still have the ability to accept cookies. We do not respond to Web browser “do not track” signals at this time. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy. For more information about “do not track,” visit [**www.allaboutdnt.org**](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).

## **Retention**

SharePoint Maven will retain your information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, for as long as your account is active, as described in this policy, or as needed to provide the Services to you. If you no longer want SharePoint Maven to use your information to provide the Services to you, you may close your account. SharePoint Maven will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your information to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws), resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and as otherwise described in this policy. We also retain log files for internal analysis purposes. These log files are generally retained for a brief period of time, except in cases where they are used for site safety and security, to improve site functionality, or we are legally obligated to retain them for longer time periods.

## **E-mail Communications** **; How to Opt-Out**

From time to time, SharePoint Maven may contact you via email for the purpose of providing announcements, promotional offers, alerts, confirmations, surveys, and/or other general communication. In order to improve our Services, we may receive a notification when you open an email from SharePoint Maven or click on a link therein.

Please note that or marketing and promotional communications are opt-in. If you would like to stop receiving marketing or promotional communications via email from SharePoint Maven, you may opt out of such communications by clicking on the UNSUBSCRIBE link.

Email marketing campaigns published by us may contain tracking facilities within the actual email. Subscriber activity is tracked and stored in a database for future analysis and evaluation. Such tracked activity may include but shall not be limited to: the opening of emails, forwarding of emails, the clicking of links within the email content, times, dates and frequency of activity. This information is used to refine future email campaigns and supply the User with more relevant content based around their activity.

## **Your Rights**

You may benefit from a number of rights in relation to your information that we process. Some rights apply only in certain limited cases, depending on your location. If you would like to manage, change, limit, or delete your personal information, you can do so by contacting us. Upon request, SharePoint Maven will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. In certain cases where we process your information, you may also have a right to restrict or limit the ways in which we use your personal information. In certain circumstances, you also have the right to request the deletion of your personal information, and to obtain a copy of your personal information in an easily accessible format. If you need further assistance, you can contact SharePoint Maven through one of the channels listed below under “Contact Information.” We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

If we process your information based on our legitimate interests as explained above, or in the public interest, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons. Where we use your data for direct marketing purposes, you can always object using the unsubscribe link in such communications.

## **Withdrawing Consent**

Where you have provided your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information. For example, you can withdraw your consent to email marketing by using the unsubscribe link in such communications. You can choose to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information at any time by emailing greg@sharepointmaven.com to request that your personal information be deleted, except for information that we are required to retain. This deletion is permanent, and your account cannot be reinstated.

## **Contact Information**

SharePoint Maven welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that SharePoint Maven has not adhered to this Statement, please contact SharePoint Maven at:

P.O. Box 1329, Summit, NJ 07902-1329, USA

Email Address:  **[greg@sharepointmaven.com](mailto:privacy@conferences.io)**

If you live in the EEA, you may also file a complaint with your local data protection regulator.
